他们现在也该上来了吧
Shouldn't they be up by now?
我肯定他们没事
I'm sure they're fine.
他们氧气会不够用的
They're gonna run out of air.
我姑娘死了倒没事
I'm happy to kill my daughter,
但你儿子没了就有点不合适了
but I feel a little awkward about killing your son.
他们能玩到一块儿
They're spending time together.
多好
It's good.
咱们现在是一家人了  他们需要亲密一些
We're a family now. They need to bond.
好吧
Yeah, well...
他们氧气够用就好
They can bond with full air intake.
朱莉  浮上来
Julie, surface now.
救命  有鲨鱼
Help! Shark!
求你了  别那么吓我
Please don't scare me like that.
什么  你说我们要友爱嘛
What? You said we should bond.
看我找到什么了
Well, look what I found.
你不该把沉船上的东西带回来
You're not supposed to take anything off the wreck.
多酷啊
How cool is this?
看起来像羽毛一样
They kind of look like feathers.
我能看看吗
Can I see?
朱莉
Julie!
给她拿个毛巾
Get her a towel.
那瓶子里究竟是什么
What was in that jar?
为什么你们不在我办公室
Why aren't you guys in my office?
为什么你在楼里  现在可是早上8点
Why are you in the building? It's 8:00 in the morning.
-奇斯在哪  -他不在
- Where's chase? - He's not here because
因为现在是早上8点
it's 8 in the morning.
16岁女孩  高烧  呕吐
16-year-old girl-- high fever, vomiting,
眼膜充血
bloodshot eyes.
多严重的流感啊
Wow. The case of the really bad flu.
我想想
Hmm, let me see.
有没漏了什么呢  对了
Did I leave anything out? Oh, yeah.
天花
The smallpox.
天花在30年前就绝迹了
Smallpox was eradicated over 30 years ago.
油炸玉米饼也是啊
So were hush puppies.
你最近没去过
Have you checked out your
附近的咖啡店吗
local hipster coffee shop lately?
天花病毒不会存在  除非在实验室
Smallpox doesn't exist outside of p4 labs
或者生化武器里
and bioweapon plants.
她当时在百慕大
She was in Bermuda.
而且潜水到过
Where she was scuba diving on the wreck
一艘被击沉的装满黑奴的荷兰运输船
of a dutch slave ship that had been intentionally sunk
因为船上爆发了天花
because an epidemic of smallpox had broken out on board.
那艘船是沉了吗
Was the ship sunk in water?
因为病毒不能在水里存活
Because viruses can't survive contact with water.
如果病毒被保存在密封的瓶子里呢
If the virus had been kept on the outside of an airtight jar,
也可能是一种情况
that might be an issue.
瓶子里有古老的接种疫苗
The jar held old-school inoculations.
他们从感染病人的痘疤上取到的
They kept the scabs of the infected people.
病毒不可能存活200多年的
The virus can't survive over 200 years.
你不就是吗
You have.
谢谢回电话
Thanks for calling back.
我是个编剧
Uh, listen, I'm a screenwriter,
理论上讲
and is it theoretically possible
天花病毒有可能
for smallpox to survive
在一个密封的玻璃瓶里
for more than 200 years underwater
存活200年以上吗
in a sealed glass jar?
理论上讲  可以  但...
Well, theoretically, yes, but--
谢谢
Thank you.
那么我们该相信哪个...
So who do we believe--
疾控中心还是青春少医呢
CDC or Dr. 90210?
隔离
Isolate,
抽血化验有无天花抗体
get baseline blood draws for smallpox antibodies
并且给这家人注射疫苗
and vaccinate the entire family.
我们应该检测21世纪的可能病毒
We should test for the 21st-century suspects--
水痘和麻疹
varicella and measles.
随便你做任何没用的检测
You're free to perform whatever unnecessary tests
只要你乐意  福曼
you want, Foreman.
奴隶制度多少年前就被废除了
Slavery was abolished years ago.
你们为什么把我们隔离在这
Why the hell do you guys have us quarantined in here?
我们只不过是做一下预防措施
We're just taking every precaution.
预防什么
Against what?
你们觉得我得了什么病
What do you think I have?
一种可能是破伤风
One possibility is tetanus
因为玻璃瓶碎片划伤了你的手
from the glass jar that sliced your hand.
我知道破伤风针
I remember tetanus shots.
可那看起来不是破伤风针
That does not look like tetanus shots.
是没必要打
It's really not worth going into,
因为可能性极大
because the odds are astronomical.
告诉我
Tell me.
再说一遍  是...
Again, it's--
天花
Smallpox.
天花吗
Smallpox?
如果你没得  疫苗会保护你
The vaccine will protect you if you don't have it
如果你得了  会减轻病情
and lessen the severity if you already do.
但可能性是十亿分之一  所以...
B-but it's a billion-to-one, so...
我们不希望你恐慌什么的
We don't want you to panic or anything.
得知这种个消息
How do I not panic
我怎么能不恐慌
with that information?
一号检查室里的白痴需要止泻药
Idiot in exam room one needs antidiarrheals
和一本字典
and a dictionary.
你现在没有门诊任务
You're not scheduled for clinic duty now.
我有空  我有四个小时债
I had some free time. I owed four hours.
你没病例要看吗
Don't you have a case?
-有啊  -那就别管这个了
- Yeah. - Then don't worry about it.
你有这么善解人意吗
Are you a stepford doctor?
如果你忙  不用来这
If you're busy, you don't need to be down here.
你是说真的
You're serious.
没错  走吧
Yep. Get out of here.
不行
I can't.
我把他的玩具动物忘在家了
I forgot her stuffed animal at home.
至今为止它一直陪着她
It's been with her
度过了每次的化疗
through all the chemo sessions so far.
我要羊羊
I need Lamby.
他不会想让我一个人看病的
He doesn't want me to do it alone.
甜心  没办法了
Honey, there's no other way.
你要勇敢点  好吗
You're just gonna have to be brave, okay?
要不我让别人和她待一会儿吧
What if I get someone to sit with her
你就能回家拿羊羊怎么样
while you run home and get Lamby?
我去叫个护士来
I'll get a nurse.
我得去处理个...
Then I have to deal with a...
非常严重的病患
very sick man.
我想她知道了
I think she knows.
她是谁  她知道了什么
Who is she, and what does she know?
卡迪  我做了个假化验单
Cuddy. And... that I faked a lab test
来骗她  为了救我的上一个病人
and lied to her to save my last patient.
她怎么做的
What did she do?
她让我离开门诊  说我有事不必去
She let me out of clinic duty by saying I had a case.
她从没那么做过
She's never done that.
她也可能从没在自助餐厅里
She's also probably never ordered the pasta special
点过意大利面
in the cafeteria.
难道那对你来说
Would that also have
也是一些让你特别恐慌的暗语吗
some special paranoid message to send you?
我没想这个
I am not imagining this.
是她对我的态度很反常
It's an aberration in the way that she treats me.
我怎么能知道这代表什么意思
How do I find out what it means?
没必要
You don't.
如果她不知道  你所做的一切
If she doesn't know, all you're gonna do
会让她怀疑你做了什么
by sniffing around is make her suspicious.
如果她知道  你会很快知道的
If she does know, you'll find out soon enough.
如果我死于这段时间内的好奇呢
What if I die of curiosity in the meantime?
你开始骗她已经够白痴了
You were an idiot for lying to her in the first place.
别再白痴下去了
Don't be more of an idiot now.
不要和谁说任何东西
Say nothing to no one about anything.
包括我
That includes me.
不是天花
It's not smallpox.
血液检查显示是其他感染
Blood work suggests some other infection.
白细胞数量下降
White count is way down.
马斯特斯  你有男朋友吗
Masters, have you got a boyfriend?
跟你没关系
That's none of your business.
可能还是个雏儿
Ah, probably just a dry spell.
豪斯  你明白
House, you do realize
我们已经排除了天花的可能吗
we just ruled out smallpox?
理论上讲  你会不会对男友格外客气
Would you ever be extra nice to a theoretical boyfriend
如果你对他很生气的话
if you were really mad at him?
我想我格外客气的唯一原因
I guess the only reason I would be extra nice
应该是我生气了  我想让他离我远点
is because I'm angry, and I just want him to go away
这样我就不必理他了
so I don't have to deal with him anymore.
你真是个咄咄逼人的坏女人
You passive/aggressive bitch.
是你问我的...
You just asked me--
福曼的无用检测做的怎么样了
What about foreman's unnecessary tests?
水痘和麻疹检测呈阴性
Negative for varicella and measles.
意思是我们的猜测都被判出局了
so all of our ideas are off the table.
我重新缕缕
I'm putting mine back on.
病人是潜水员
Patient's a diver.
在强大压力下  血液中每项物质
Under increased pressure, everything in the blood
都受到惊吓  恐慌  奔腾  躲藏
gets scared, panics, runs, and hides.
抗体可能在关节处
Antibodies could be in the joints.
轻敲她的膝盖  脚踝  肩膀
Tap her knee, ankle, shoulder,
去检查她那天花满满的身体的关节处
and any other joint in her smallpox-ridden body.
对话不错
Good talk.
你知道了
You know.
当然我知道了
Of course I know.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank god.
我想我刚刚想太多了
I thought I was just being paranoid.
为什么你啥也不说
Why didn't you say something?
因为我想让你自己来向我道歉
'cause I wanted you to come to me and apologize.
我没做错是不会道歉的
I can't apologize if I haven't done anything wrong.
你在我眼前撒谎
You lied to my face.
为了工作
To do my job,
为了救病人的命
to save a patient's life.
我不想在你面前扮教父
Look, I don't want to go all godfather on you.
这是工作
This was business.
私底下我是不会向你撒谎的
I wouldn't lie to you about something personal.
你不允许向我说任何谎言
Well, you don't get to lie to me about anything.
我可没法分清公私
I can't compartmentalize my life like that.
也许你该习惯  因为随时会这样
Well, maybe you should practice, 'cause it comes in handy.
我想你该走了
I think you should go.
对不起
Sorry.
我得把针插入骨头后面
I have to get the needle behind the bone.
我骨头疼死了
I'm running out of bones.
如果这是浪费时间...
If this is a waste of time--
最后一个
Last one.
你只需要
You just have to be...
怎么了
What?
到底怎么了
What--what is it?
抱歉  我必须上报疾控中心
I'm sorry. I have to call the CDC.
我想你真的得了天花
I think you do have smallpox.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
恐怖分子就会用天花病毒
I mean, this is what terrorists want to use
来杀人对吧
to kill everyone, right?
好像是不治之症
Like, there's no cure.
有治疗的办法  可以用西多福韦
There are treatments. We can give you cidofovir.
我想你关心的不是药名
I don't think you care about the drugs' names.
说到底  有30%死亡率
Bottom line-- it's 30% fatal,
即是说你活命的概率
which means your chances of being okay
和篮球运动员罚中球
are about the same as a basketball player's chance
差不多
at hitting a free throw,
除非她皮肤上有黑紫斑
unless she finds dark, purplish skin blotches.
黑紫斑能说明什么
What would purple blotches mean?
出血性天花
Hemorrhagic-type smallpox.
这种情况  她活下来的机会就好比
In which case, her chances are more like...
奥尼尔罚中球
Shaq hitting a free throw.
紫斑是没有  不过看看这个
Well, no purple skin, but take a look at this.
是什么
What is it?
您女儿腋下出皮疹
There's a rash under your daughter's arm.
还是那些恶心的脓包吗
Like more of those gross bumps?
不是  这些只是一般的疹子
No. It's just a regular rash.
这又说明什么
W-what does that mean?
说明你得的不是天花
It means it's not smallpox.
你是说你理解豪斯的立场
Are you saying you see House's side?
根本算不上立场  完全是找借口
It's not even a side. It's a fictional construction.
她指望豪斯实话实说
She's expecting House not to lie?
她要是靠和豪斯的关系
If she's using the relationship
就想试图改变豪斯
as a rationale to try to change things--
等等  这是表示
Wait. Wait. Are you saying
我俩互相撒谎没关系吗
it's okay for us to lie to each other?
不  我们的关系不同
No, we have a different relationship--
比他俩健康多了
I think a better one.
我们之间没有谎言
Lying was never part of it.
他们的关系则是建立在谎话之上
Theirs is built on it.
抱歉  得走了
Sorry, I have to go.
不要吧  我再过五分钟也要上班去
Oh, come on, I have to leave in, like, five minutes.
-不能等等吗  -有个小女孩
- Can't it wait? - There's a little girl.
照看她的护士被叫走了
The nurse watching her got called away.
说来话长  总之我成了保姆
It's a long story, but I've got to babysit.
晚上见
I'll see you tonight.
请注意  从现在起
Attention-- effective immediately,
全院所有出入口暂时关闭
all hospital entrances and exits will be restricted
请等待进一步通知
until further notice.
疾病防治中心下令
Center for disease control has ordered
普林斯顿普雷斯波罗教学医院全面封锁
Princeton plainsboro hospital locked down.
看来我可以留下了
Well, I guess I can stay.
请几位离开房间
Please step out of the room.
我是布洛塔医生  疾控中心感染管理办主任
I'm Dr. Broda, head of infection control, CDC.
你们的防护服不合格
And your protective suits are not adequate.
其实吧我们不穿都没事
Turns out they don't have to be.
腋下皮疹说明并非天花
Rash under the arm means it's not smallpox.
虚惊一场  抱歉了
False alarm. Sorry.
祝你们一路顺风
Hope the traffic wasn't too bad.
皮疹正是天花的临床表现
Rash is consistent with smallpox.
但出现在脓疱之后就不是
Not if it presents after pustules.
她大概只是对床单或病员服过敏
She's probably just allergic to the bedsheets
你之前没注意到罢了
or the hospital gown, and you simply didn't notice it.
我们要空运血液和组织样本去亚特兰大
We're gonna airlift blood and tissue samples to Atlanta.
十八小时之后可以拿到DNA化验结果
We'll have the DNA results in 18 hours.
与此同时
In the meantime, please,
请离开隔离病房
step out of the room.
你连飞机都带来了  酷
You brought the plane? Cool.
我们走了之后
When we left, Julie's fever
朱莉的体温攀升到39度以上
had climbed to over 103.
这不是天花  她不会死
It's not smallpox. She's not dying.
所以这病例不归我们管了
And it's not our case.
还有什么舍不得的吗
Need any other reasons to forget it?
知道怎么看出来没有事可做了吗
You know how you can tell there's nothing to be done?
-奇斯出现  -我九点才来的好吧
- Chase showed up. - I was here at 9:00.
那你们是打算下面十八个钟头啥都不干
So you guys just want to do nothing for the next 18 hours
干等人家告诉我们这不是天花
until they tell us it's not smallpox?
我们就不能花时间讨论一下
Can't we spend the time discussing
看起来像天花却不是天花的病是什么
what looks like smallpox but isn't smallpox?
接触传染性软疣
Molluscum contagiosum.
需要比照病灶来做鉴别诊断
You have to compare lesions to differentiate.
可我们不能接触病人
But we don't have access to the patient
没法获取新的情况
or any new information.
但我们可以获取其他病人的情况
But we do have access to the other patients--
那些1793年死于同一种病的人
The ones who died of the same thing in 1793.
这是索托斯号的船长日志
It's the captain's log from the Sotos Ooslerzoon.
百慕大海事博物馆好心发来一份PDF
Maritime museum in Bermuda graciously sent over a PDF.
问题解决了
Problem solved.
我想你们起码有一个会说荷兰语吧
I assume at least one of you speaks fluent Dutch.
荷兰现在是大半夜的
It's the middle of the night in the Netherlands.
没人在上班
Nobody's working.
不愁找不到人的
Oh, you can always find someone.
哦  没错  我的名字叫格尔特
Oh, yes. My name is Geerte.
你是最英俊性感的
Are you handsome,
美国男人吗
sexiest American man?
你知道  有些人
You know, some people--
我就承认吧  我是
I would say that I am, yeah.
我想要你帮我翻译点东西
I want you to translate something for me.
翻译多没意思
Why you want I translate?
我可以不穿衣服调情  玩具系列  还可以
I do topless, toys, and--
赶紧翻译吧
Just do the translation.
人家怎么舒服就怎么翻
She can translate however she feels most comfortable.
随你便
Whatever.
你输入信用卡号
You put in credit card.
豪斯  医院有翻译随时待命
House, the hospital has translators on call--
闭嘴
Shut up.
亲爱的  能给我们的新朋友
Honey, could you email our new friend
-发份船长日志吗  -没问题
- the captain's log? - Sure thing...
最性感的美国男人
Sexiest american man.
七月十四日早上
"On morning of 14, July,
我带着两箱行李和我的猫登上了索托斯号
I boarded Sotos Ooslerzoon with two trunks and my cat."
船长养了只猫呀
Aw! The captain had a cat.
这姑娘可爱吧
Isn't she adorable?
往下直接跳到
Go ahead and skip to the part
大家生病的部分
where people get sick.
找到了
Mm...ah, here.
乘客发烧了  不停颤抖  眼镜还红红的
"The passenger has a fever, shaking, and red eyes."
非洲人还尿了裤子
Ooh. Also African man make go in his pants.
那船长和船员呢
What about the captain, the crew?
没事  上面说只有非洲人生病了
Mm, no. It say only African men sick.
不可能是天花
It can't be smallpox.
既然通过空气传播
Airborne transmission
每个人感染的风险都是一样的
Means it's an equal-opportunity killer.
原来我们查的这病歧视人啊
We're looking for a disease that discriminates.
镰状细胞
Sickle cell.
不一定是种族歧视
The disease doesn't have to be racist.
可以是阶级偏见
It could be classist.
光照不足导致的维生素D缺乏症
Vitamin "D" Deficiency from lack of sunlight
会削弱免疫系统
weakens the immune system, makes the slaves
使得那些奴隶更易感染疟疾和登革热
more vulnerable to malaria or dengue fever.
这些病又不会有脓疱
I don't know how you get pustules from any of those.
船长和船员有清洁的饮用水
Captain and crew got clean drinking water.
而奴隶们有什么喝什么
Slaves drank whatever they could.
瘰[淋巴结核]
Scrofula.
这就是十八世纪人们所说的
That's what they called cervical T.B. Lymphadenitis
颈部结核性淋巴腺炎
in The 1700s.
患了淋巴结核病
Scrofulicious--
这是十八世纪人们所说的"烦人的病"
That's what they called "annoying" in the 1700s.
她说错了吗
Is she wrong?
那他们白死了
Then they died for nothing.
这些奴隶原本可以帮我祖先除除草
Those slaves could have led long, fulfilling lives
过着长寿而充实的生活
mowing my ancestors' lawns.
福曼
Foreman.
能和你去外面说两句吗
Can I speak to you outside for a second?
我们需要检验结核
We need to test for T.B.
说不定真是结核
T.B. might fit,
可这病又不会那么快致命
but it's too slow-moving to kill her anytime soon.
疾控中心的人不可能马上放我们进去做测试
There's no way the CDC's gonna give us access.
因此我们不说是结核
That's why we don't think it's T.B.
就说是脑膜炎球菌类疾病
We think it's meningococcal disease,
不等结果出来她就会没命
which could kill her before the results come back.
他一给我放行  我就去测结核
And once I gain access, I run the T.B. test.
这些话没必要在外面说吧
You could have said all that in there.
当着缉毒女警的面吗  能成吗
In front of the narc? As if.
你就这么怕这个新来的女孩
Are you so afraid of this new girl,
每次你要挑战道德底线的时候
we have to take elaborate measures
我们都得大费周章
every time you want to skirt around ethical boundaries?
大费周章  出来走走嘛
Elaborate measures? We took a walk--
早晚你也要走出房间的
A walk you would have taken anyway.
事实上  诊断完等大伙儿一起出来
Actually, I saved you from the horrible
还挤得慌呢
post-differential traffic jam.
脑膜炎球菌
Meningococcus.
我们认为朱莉腋下的皮疹
We believe the rash under Julie's armpit
其实是瘀点
is actually petechial spots.
再考虑到高热  呕吐
When added to the high fever, the vomiting--
目前尚未出现痉挛  也没有颈脖僵直
There haven't been any seizures, no stiff neck.
只要让我进去看看病人
If I could just gain access to the patient,
我可以更仔细观察皮疹
I can investigate the rash further.
我会去看的
I'll take a look.
我可以穿你的防护服
I can wear your gear.
做好任何必要预防措施
I'll take every necessary precaution.
你跑来给我个没把握的诊断
You come to me with a weak diagnosis.
我主动提出帮你诊察
I even offer to investigate,
但你还不满意
But that's not good enough for you.
你到底打的什么注意
What's really going on here?
先生
Sir...
你感到任何不适吗
Are you feeling all right in there?
我头疼
It's just a headache.
老公
Baby.
爸爸
Dad...
你在流血
You're bleeding.
快来人啊
Somebody, please...
快进来啊
Get in here now!
这不是脑膜炎球菌
This is not meningococcus.
你不许进来
You're not getting in here.
-酷  -哪里酷  他们家病更重了
- Cool. - Not really--not for them
你也诊断错了  那个爸爸的新症状
and not for you-- the dad's new symptoms
和感染天花病毒相吻合
are consistent with them having smallpox.
如果他头疼才吻合
Would be if he had a headache.
他就是头疼啊
He does have a headache.
不  他只是"噢"了一声  然后捧着头
No. He just said, "Ow," And held his head.
事实上  他"噢"了一声
Actually, he said, "Ow."
然后说"我头疼"
Then he said, "It's a headache."
这只能预示头部有疼痛感
Which could be indicative of head pain.
头疼由肌肉紧张
Headache is caused by
或者血管拉伸引起
muscle tension or vascular stretching.
而头部疼痛感是由创伤引起
Head pain is caused by trauma, which would include
比如说结核导致的脑出血
Such events as a bleed in the brain from T.B.
-又回到结核了  -一直在说它
- We're back to T.B.? - We never left.
我们需要做个断层扫描
We'll need to do a C.T.
我有预感疾控中心的人
And I sort of have a hunch that the CDC's
是不会同意我们移动病人的
not gonna approve of us moving the patient.
奇斯  能和你去外面说两句吗
Chase, can I talk to you outside for a second?
你用过这招了
You just tried this.
我撒谎水平不比福曼高
I'm not a better liar than Foreman.
你比他强多了
Sure, you are.
你可是罪犯的传人啊
You're descended from convicts.
况且这次不需要说谎
Plus, there's no lie this time.
我们挂羊头卖狗肉
It's a bait and switch.
你提出个做气脑造影的建议
You propose that we don't have to move him
气脑造影:将脑脊液放出,代之以气体(空气或氧气)
使脑室密度降低,以在X光片上显影的检查方法
这样我们就不用转移病人
if we do a pneumoencephalograph.
这是60年前的技术  很多病人因此丧命
That's 60-year-old technology that killed patients.
就要这个效果
Exactly.
他会做出让步允许我们做断层扫描
He'll compromise on the C.T.
他可不是卡迪
This isn't Cuddy.
你这种绝地武士式的思维控制对他不管用
Your Jedi mind tricks won't work here.
这不是你们要找的机器人
These aren't the droids you're looking for.
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
背着你做事情
Going behind your back
不被你发现效果更好
works better when you're not facing us.
不管你打算对布洛塔说什么谎
Instead of whatever lie you're gonna tell Broda,
何不告诉他真相呢
why don't you just tell him the truth?
如果我们坦诚相待  跟他讲明白道理
If we are honest and reasonable--
全世界的人民  无论种族宗教
People of all races and creeds
都能够和平共处  和谐生存
will live together in peace and harmony.
之前的计划结果如何
How did your first plan work out?
按你说的办吧
Permission granted.
谢谢
Thank you.
她被拒绝后  马上按我们的计划行事
After she gets denied, do the bait and switch.
他们不让你妈妈回到医院来
They won't let your mommy back in the hospital
是因为楼下发生了紧急事件
because of an emergency downstairs.
但我们真得开始化疗了
But we have to get started.
羊羊不在我不干
I can't do it without my Lamby.
她是谁呀
Who is she?
谁都不是  我马上就走
I'm nobody. I'm leaving soon.
她叫萨姆  是我的朋友
Her name is Sam, and she's a friend of mine.
你平时化疗的时候  羊羊都干点什么呢
What does Lamby usually do while you get your treatment?
他会握着我的手
He holds my hand.
你可以握着我的手呀
Well, you could hold my hand.
这不管用
That won't work.
有的时候我们必须做一些
Well, sometimes we have to do things
我们不想做的事情
that we don't want to do.
比如必须上学  必须吃蔬菜
You have to go to school. You have to eat your vegetables.
必须吃药
You have to take your medicine.
必须的
You have to.
我要妈妈
I want my mommy.
好
Yeah.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
我相信在楼下商店里能找到
You know, I'm pretty sure Lamby has a cousin
羊羊的兄弟姐妹
down in the gift shop.
稍等一下
Hold off a minute.
现在是加时赛
I'm in overtime.
布洛塔同意给孩子爸爸做断层扫描
Uh, Broda agreed to C.T. The dad's brain.
真没意思
Well, that sucks.
这不是你想要的结果么
But I thought that's what you wanted.
不应该通过讲实话得来
I shouldn't have gotten it with the truth.
他是个伪君子
He's a hypocrite.
从他到这儿起立场完全是...
His position ever since he's been here has been--
我跟他说  如果我们对了
I-I pointed out that either we're right,
他就是化解这次危机的英雄
and he's the hero for ending the crisis,
如果他对了  他就可以第一个看到
or he's right, and he gets to be the first person
感染天花的大脑
to look at a brain infected with smallpox.
三十年前断层扫描还没发明
C.T. scans weren't around 30 years ago.
干得不错
Good work.
看来诚实真是上上策
So I guess honesty is the best policy.
说这话干嘛  真的
Why'd you say that? Seriously...
想表明你的观点  好像我还不知道似的
To establish your viewpoint, as if I didn't already know it,
还是想展示你跟卡迪
or to demonstrate some weird
有种灵异的跨越代沟的姊妹情谊
cross-generational female solidarity with Cuddy?
我只想缓解一下没话可说的尴尬局面
Actually, I was just trying to fill the awkward silence.
他们怎么停下了
Why have they stopped?
你不能过去
You can't go out there.
你们怎么停下了
Why did you stop?
快离开走廊
Get out of the hallway.
他又没感染天花
He does not have smallpox.
他也得了
Yes, he does.
好痒
It itches.
他身上刚刚出现脓疱
He's just developed pustules.
现在转移他的风险太大了
He's now too dangerous to transport.
快离开走廊
Get out of the hallway.
孩子爸爸的生命体征很差
Dad's vitals are in the toilet.
达到天花发病极期
He's got full-blown smallpox.
他女儿怎么样了
What about the daughter?
脓疱数量剧增  生命体征特极差
Pustule count is way up. Vitals are way down.
说明我想错了
Means I was wrong.
但准确地讲  在我想错之前我是对的
But to be precise, I was right before I was wrong, so...
我们就这样放弃回家了
So we just give up and go home?
事实上医院大门紧锁
Actually, somebody locked the front door,
但我们确实只能放弃了
but, yeah, we... give up.
-我们应该继续  -我们已经做出诊断
- We might as well keep... - We have our diagnosis.
如果你想积极表现  可以去找个新病人
If you're eager, you can go find us a new case.
她要么是太积极了  要么就是无法理解讽刺
I guess she's eager or has a blind spot for sarcasm.
我只想看看她胳膊下面的脓疱
I just want to look at the rash under her arm
看看是否已经成熟
to see if it's matured--
-你可以隔着玻璃看  -我想更近一些
- You can look through the glass. - I need to be closer.
如果脓疱发展的程度不一致
If the pustules are at a different stage--
她现在没有痛苦
She's comfortable.
八个小时后结果就出来了
We're gonna have our results back in eight hours.
如果不是天花  可以让你第一个进去看
If it's not smallpox, you can be the first one in there.
你站在外面干什么
Why are you just standing out there?
我只是想帮你
I'm just trying to help.
不知道你有没有力气
If you're feeling up to it,
坐起来让我看一下你胳膊下面的脓疱
can you sit up and show me the rash under your arm?
等等
Uh, wait.
你脚掌上一个脓疱都没有
The soles of your feet. There aren't any lesions.
管脚掌干吗
Who cares?
别的地方到处都是  简直是在受刑
They're everywhere else. This is torture.
伊芙
Eve?
猜猜谁来医院看你了
Guess who came by the hospital for a visit?
伊芙你好
Hello, Eve.
哦  不
Oh, no!
好吧
All right.
我去叫几个特别和蔼的护士来
I'm gonna get a couple of nice nurses to come in here,
帮你们两个做好化疗准备  行吗
and get you two ready for the treatment, all right?
好的
Okay.
为什么羊羊可以进来妈妈却不行
How come Lamby can be here but mommy can't?
羊羊有点脏  我们给他洗了个澡
Lamby was dirty. Um, we gave her a bath.
它不是羊羊
This isn't lamby!
朱莉得的不是天花
Julie doesn't have smallpox.
刚才终于认同了天花的诊断
Did I just dream the part
难道我当时是在做梦
where I finally agreed it was smallpox?
如果我以为是事实的东西
Well, if what I thought was reality
实际上是梦境  那反之亦然
was actually a dream, then the reverse...
哦  天呐
Oh, my god.
我曾经跟嘎嘎夫人和碧昂丝一起玩3P
I had a threesome with Beyonce and Lady Gaga.
她手掌和脚掌上
She doesn't have pustules on her palms
没有脓疱
or the soles of her feet.
但他爸爸有
The dad does have pustules there.
天花怎么跳过她染上她爸的
So how does he get smallpox, but it skips her?
我像那样跑出去  你应该跟上
If I leave like that, you should follow.
哦
Oh.
我们让他染上的
We gave it to him.
奇斯哪里去了
Where's Chase?
我们并不住在一起  你知道吧
You do realize we don't all live together, right?
这样啊...  我们让他感染了天花
Well, then just.. we gave it to him.
女儿的手掌上没有脓疱  所以...
No pustules on the daughter's palms, so...
所以你认为
So therefore your theory is
你让我去抽孩子爸爸的血
you asked me to take the dad's blood,
但我不小心给他注射了天花病毒
but I accidentally injected him with smallpox.
千真万确  虽然严格来讲是牛痘病毒
Exactly, although technically, it was the vaccinia virus,
用来制作天花疫苗的原料
which is what the smallpox vaccine is made from.
跟天花症状相同
Same symptoms as smallpox,
但毒性只有一半而且几乎不致死
but only half the calories and almost none of the lethality.
听起来像个反疫苗狂的言论
You sound like one of those anti-vaccine cranks.
接种天花疫苗受感染
You can't develop full-blown symptoms
不可能这么快就进入极期
from the vaccine this quickly.
免疫功能受损就有可能
You can if you're immunocompromised.
只有我读病史吗
Am I the only one who reads these things?
-她爸得过肾癌  -六年前的事
- Dad had kidney cancer. - Six years ago.
-他已经康复了  -现在显然复发了
- He's been in remission. - Well, it's obviously back.
破坏了他的免疫系统
Shot his immune system,
使他失去对牛痘病毒的防御能力
made him vulnerable to the vaccinia,
用干扰素可以让他好转
which will get better on interferon.
所以如果干扰素治疗起作用
So if he responds to the treatment,
就能证明他得的不是天花
that proves he doesn't have smallpox.
那他女儿得的是什么
Then what does the daughter have?
妈的  我还在幻想你不会问这个问题
Damn. I was hoping you weren't gonna ask me that.
麻烦先集中精力对付
Can we please just focus
有诊断可治疗的疾病
on the disease we just diagnosed and can treat?
你说哪种更有可能
What's more likely-- he got smallpox
接种疫苗第二天就感染天花
the day after we immunized him for it,
还是疫苗本身使他感染
or he's sick from the vaccine itself?
你有肾癌复发的证据吗
You got any proof the kidney cancer is back?
让我给他用这个药
Well, let me give him this.
他病情好转就是你想要的证据
When he gets better, that'll be the proof you need.
我可以穿上你们的高档太空服
I'll put on one of your fancy spacesuits,
而且我保证不会亲吻他的开放性脓疱
and I promise I won't kiss him on an open sore.
你知道珍妮特·派克是谁吗
You know who Janet Parker is?
1978年
In 1978,
她在英国一所大学工作
she was working at a university in England.
楼下一间实验室的工作人员出了岔子
Someone in a research lab on the floor below screwed up.
天花病毒
Some smallpox virus managed to
从通风系统向上飘
float up through the vents
进入到她的办公室
into the room where she was working.
四天之后她就死了
She died four days later--
她是已知死于天花的最后一人
the last known person to die from smallpox.
实验室的负责人自责太深
And the person in charge of the lab was so destroyed,
最后自杀了
he killed himself.
他皮肤开始剥落
Now that he's shedding,
我不能放任何人进去
I can't open that door for anyone.
看  那就是你要的证据
Look, there's the proof you need.
尿袋里有血
There's blood in the urine bag.
他的肾脏正在衰竭
His kidneys are shutting down.
他已经到了病程末期
He's in the final stages of the disease.
如果肾衰竭是天花导致的
If smallpox was causing the kidney failure,
血应该是棕色
the blood would be brown.
血呈红色是因为肾癌复发
It's red because the kidney cancer is back,
他感染的不是天花
and this is not smallpox.
我不会把门打开
I'm not opening that door.
你不开我开
Well, that makes one of us.
嘿  你简直疯了
Hey! You're insane!
但我的诊断是正确的
But I'm right.
希望你是正确的
I hope you are,
因为现在我不能让你出来了
because I can't let you out now.
这就是你的下场
This is what happens
不尊重权威
when you have no respect for authority,
不尊重任何人
no respect for anything.
你不觉得有点太过分吗
You don't think it's a little much
用死亡相威胁
to use the threat of death
来赢取和男友的一场不相干的争吵
to win a totally separate argument with your boyfriend?
你以为我在说另一件事
You think this is about the other thing?
跟那件事情貌似差不离
Does seem to track suspiciously closely.
现在我不在乎你对我撒谎
I don't care right now that you lied to me.
我要你活下去
I want you to stay alive.
如果我活下来了  是不是意味着两场架我都赢了
And if I do, does that mean I win both arguments?
把隔离服穿上
Put the suit on.
没必要吧  妈
It's unnecessary, Mom.
这就是为什么我不希望他们告诉你
This is why I didn't want them telling you.
也是为什么我很高兴他们没有告诉威尔森
It's why I'm glad they didn't tell Wilson.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
我的病情加重了是吗
I'm getting worse, aren't I?
干扰素发挥效用需要时间
Interferon takes a little time to work.
别担心
Don't worry.
告诉布洛塔
Tell Broda
我在给他加氧
that I'm increasing his oxygen.
把我的小组都叫过来
And get my team down here.
你好啊
Hi.
生我们气了  对不对
You're mad at us, aren't you?
-嗯  -你生气是应该的
- Yeah. - Well, you have a right to be.
我们骗你了
We weren't honest.
你可能还不知道
You might not know this yet,
但有时大人会做错事
but sometimes adults mess up.
我告诉你个事儿
Can I tell you something,
你能帮我保密吗
and you keep it just between us?
我不太会与小孩子相处
I'm not great with kids.
我喜欢孩子  但我害怕
I love them, but I get scared
自己会做错事情
that I'm gonna do the wrong thing,
而且通常都会
and then... I usually do.
刚才我说谎就是
And that's what I did with the lying.
真的很抱歉
And I'm very sorry about that.
我之所以做错误的事
The reason why I did the wrong thing
是希望你可以
was because I was trying to get you
做正确的事
to do the right thing.
你的妈妈和你的羊羊
Your mommy and your Lamby
都希望你好起来
both really need you to get better.
那
So...
你说
Do you think that...
你可以勇敢点
You could be really brave...
去做正确的事情吗
And do the right thing?
我会努力的
I'll try.
好样的
Great.
热度很高  氧饱和度很低
Fever's way up. Sat's way down.
脓疱还在扩散
Pustules still spreading.
干扰素没起效
Interferon's not working.
所以这就是天花
Which means this is smallpox.
说得好
Right!
因为这大千世界只有两种病
'cause there are only two diseases
想想还能是什么
in the whole wide world-- what else could it be?
一定还有别的
There's got to be something.
不  不可能
No, there doesn't.
她的脚上仍然没出现脓疱
There are still no pustules on her feet.
你认为不是天花的理由依旧成立
All the reasons you thought it wasn't smallpox still exist.
别管她的脚  别管那些原因
Forget her feet. Forget all those other reasons.
看看他  疱疹是圆凸状的
Look at him now. The pox are dome-shaped.
他身上80%的地方都长满了
They're on 80% of his body, and
而且没有结痂
they're not scabbing over.
这是典型的天花
This is textbook smallpox.
这时候再做鉴别诊断也没用
DDX'ing at this point isn't gonna make a difference.
-别那么说  -很抱歉
- Don't say that. - I'm sorry.
豪斯
House...
你闯进去犯了大错
You screwed up going in there.
感觉发热了吗
You have any fever?
还没
Not yet.
等我真的发热了
But when it does come,
你恐怕就会意识到为我撒谎而生气
I assume you'll see the pettiness
其实是多么小气
of being mad at me for lying.
闭嘴  豪斯
Shut up, House.
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
我活不成了  是不是
I'm not gonna make it, am I?
你该向你的家人道别了
You should say good-bye to your family.
我爱你
I love you.
坚持住
Just hold on.
顽强点
Fight this.
帮我照顾好儿子
You got to take care of my boy.
不
No.
答应我
Promise me.
我答应你
I promise.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
让罗杰过来
Get Roger closer.
到这边来
Come closer.
来吧
Come on.
老爸
Dad.
我的宝贝儿子
My baby boy.
老爸  别
Dad, please...
一切都会好起来的
It's gonna be okay.
露露会照顾好你的
Lulu's gonna take care of you.
我不要她  老爸
I don't want her, dad.
她代替不了你
She's not you.
我会永远爱你  罗杰
I will always love you, Roger.
老爸
Dad?
你要害死我
You're killing me!
如果你还没感染的话
The suit will protect you
隔离服能保护你
if you haven't already been exposed.
我的氧气快耗尽了
My air supply's almost out.
我们会再给你一罐的
We'll give you another canister.
换氧气瓶的时候我就会接触到病毒
Yeah, and when I change it, I will be exposed.
赶快转移他吧
Just move him!
我希望我可以
I wish I could.
那太好了
Oh, that's great,
你知道你可以做什么吗
'cause you know what you can do?
转移我
You can move me.
你还不知道我得没得天花
You don't know that I have smallpox yet.
我们必须作此打算
We have to assume.
五楼还有一个隔离间
There's another isolation room on the fifth floor.
问题是如何把他转移到那儿
The problem is getting him from here to there.
就是不方便喽
So it's inconvenient.
你不方便给我个机会
My having a fighting chance at life
争取活命
is inconvenient!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们不确定他是否会染上
We don't know that he'll catch it.
我们也不确定那一定就是天花
We don't know that it's definitely smallpox,
只有等疾控中心DNA化验结果出来
not until we get the DNA results back from the CDC.
你以为那个爸爸怎么死的
What do you think the dad just died of?
跟他们说说理会死吗
Would it kill us to talk it through?
不会  也救不了豪斯
Kill us? No. Save house? Also no.
哪怕奇迹出现  不是天花
Even if by some miracle it's not smallpox,
我们也无能为力
there's nothing more for us to go on.
没有新的病例资料
There's no new data.
也不会再有任何
And there isn't going to be any--
-你要去哪儿  -找新的资料
- Where are you going?  - To get more data.
"格丽特看上去很冷漠
"Gerritt seems distant
心事重重"
and preoccupied."
谁是格丽特  他是个奴隶吗
Who's Gerritt? Is he a slave?
格丽特是船长的猫
Gerritt is the captain's kitty.
船长的猫有心事
The captain's cat is preoccupied?
别管猫了
Skip the cat.
宰了只羊做晚餐
Uh, "One goat slaughtered for dinner.
又新开一桶葡萄酒
Broke out the next barrel of wine."
也别管吃的了
Skip the food.
再回头说说猫吧
Uh, c-can we go back to the cat?
那只猫病了吗
Did the cat get sick?
天花只感染人类
Smallpox is exclusive to humans.
船长不养宠物
Ship captains didn't have pets.
如果没有特殊目的
Nothing and nobody went on those ships
不会带宠物上船吧
if it didn't have a purpose.
-抓老鼠吗  -为了船员们好
- Hunting mice and rats?  - For the crew.
船舱里也许有鼠患
The hold was probably infested with mice.
如果这就是问题关键呢
What if that's the difference?
格丽特到底怎么了
What happened to Gerritt?
啊
Ah.
你这"啊"是难过还是开心
Is that a sad "Ah" Or a cute "Ah"?
格丽特死了  当然是难过了
Gerritt, he died. It's a sad "Ah."
它死之前掉毛没有
Before he died, did he lose his fur?
你怎么知道
How did you know?
老鼠不会携带天花病毒
Mice don't carry smallpox,
但携带立克次体痘疹
but they do carry rickettsialpox.
这个可以治愈
Which is treatable.
给他们用多西环素
Just start them on Doxycycline.
就因为一只秃毛的猫
Based on a bald cat?
你没听过动物换毛吗
You never heard of shedding?
用了有什么坏处
What's the downside?
如果我们给她用一堆抗菌素和抗病毒药物
If we shove her full of antibiotics plus the antivirals,
会抑制她的骨髓
it'll suppress her bone marrow.
那个女孩都快死了
That girl's about to die.
可能是吧
She probably is,
但我不想冒险把她推向死亡边缘
and I don't want to risk pushing her over the edge.
起码查看下爸爸的尸体
At least look at the Dad's body.
如果有小块黑死组织就证明我是对的
Small patches of black, dead tissue will prove I'm right.
立克次体痘疹会出现焦痂
Eschars appear with rickettsialpox
天花则不会
but not with smallpox.
如果他出现了焦痂  我不可能没注意到
If he had developed eschars, I would have noticed.
你好几个小时都没靠近他五米之内
You haven't been within 20 feet of the guy in hours.
让他们查查看
Have them check.
他们的工作就是消毒尸体
Their job is to bleach the body,
杀灭病毒
kill the virus,
移出尸体  都是为了豪斯医生
and get it out of there for Dr. House's sake.
消毒尸体
Bleaching the body
会销毁立克次体感染的证据
will destroy all evidence of rickettsialpox.
根本就没有什么证据
There is no evidence!
我不想任何人受伤害
I'm not trying to hurt anyone here.
我也不想骗你
I'm not lying to you.
这就是天花
This is smallpox.
豪斯  你得检查一下尸体
House, you have to examine the body.
我才不会靠近那儿
I'm not going anywhere near it.
找找焦痂  快点
Look for eschars. Hurry.
你认为是立克次体
You think it's r-pox?
船长有只猫
The captain had a cat.
先是掉毛  然后死了
He lost his fur and then died.
退后  豪斯医生
Step back, Dr. House.
戴手套做尸检很难
It's kind of hard to do an autopsy in oven mitts.
脱掉啊
Take them off.
说得轻巧
Says the woman
你可是站在两层隔离窗外面
standing behind two panes of glass.
你相信我吗
Do you believe me?
不说我  你相信你自己吗
Forget me. Do you believe you?
你也认为是立克次体痘疹  对吧
You think it's rickettsialpox, don't you?
如果是  就可以治愈
If it is, it's curable,
除非我们能证明这点否则她必死无疑
and she's gonna die unless we can prove it.
你真的很讨人厌
You really are annoying.
加油  豪斯  加油
Come on, House. Come on.
焦痂
Eschar.
Eschars.
马上给她用多西环素
Start the girl on doxycycline right now.
妈咪
Mommy!
你和她处得很好啊
You were good with her.
是啊  可是之前很糟糕
Yeah, only after being bad.
需要练习嘛
It takes practice.
或许我应该养只小狗
Maybe I should get a puppy.
行啊  或者  怀个孩子
Yeah, or... pregnant?
你会好起来的
You're gonna be okay.
我请你吃早饭
Buy you breakfast?
不  谢了
No, thanks.
要是觉得我在养你  你可以买单
You can pay...If it's starting to feel like I'm carrying you.
豪斯  别这样
House, stop.
我快没命那会儿
When I was dying...
是谁说同事间那点善意的谎言
You realized that a little white lie between coworkers
没什么大不了的
wasn't such a big deal.
是  这话没错
Yeah, and that was true...
在你快死的时候
When you were dying.